Finding Aid for Ann Arbor - Washtenaw Council of Churches records, 1928-1969
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Ann Arbor - Washtenaw Council of Churches records 1928-1969
Ann Arbor - Washtenaw Council of Churches.
2 linear feet.
8535 Ba 2
Bulletins, minutes of committees, correspondence, news clippings, and other materials relating to the activities of the organization; also minutes, 1928-1953, of Ann Arbor Ministerial Association.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was deposited by the Ann Arbor Council of Churches (donor no. 6224 ) in 1978.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Ann Arbor Ministerial Association was established in 1928. Its purpose was to "coordinate the plans and activities of the religious forces of Ann Arbor in regard to all matters of common interest and responsibility, to give united expression to religious conviction and conscience in matters of moral significance and social relationships ..." Some time in the 1940s, a separate organization -- the Ann Arbor Council of Churches -- was formed. The membership of this group included both clergy and laypeople. This organization gradually came to encompass like-minded people beyond Ann Arbor. Accordingly, the name of the organization was changed to the Ann Arbor - Washtenaw Council of Churches.
The record group is comprised of two series: Ann Arbor Ministerial Association and Ann Arbor-Washtenaw Council of Churches Yearly Files. The kinds of documents in the Ann Arbor Ministerial Association series includes minutes of meetings, scattered correspondence and financial reports. The Ann Arbor-Washtenaw Council of Churches Yearly Files also includes minutes as well as greater documentation of projects and services provided by the organization.
Subjects:
Clergy--Michigan--Washtenaw County.; Washtenaw County (Mich.).; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Church history.; Ann Arbor Ministerial Association (Mich.).
- Ann Arbor Ministerial Association
  - Minutes (with financial reports, resolutions and correspondence), 1928-1953, 5 folders (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1962-1963, 1965-1967 (Box 1)
- Ann Arbor-Washtenaw Council of Churches Yearly Files
  - 1944-1949 (Box 1)
  - 1950-1951 (Box 1)
  - 1953-1957, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - 1958
    - Administration (Box 1)
    - Social Services (Box 1)
  - 1959
    - Administration (Box 1)
    - Social Services (Box 1)
  - 1960
    - Administration (Box 1)
    - United Services and Christian Education (Box 1)
    - Social Services (Box 1)
    - Youth for Understanding, Michigan Teen-age Exchange (Box 1)
  - 1961
    - Administration (Box 1)
    - United Services and Christian Education, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Social Services, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 1962
    - Administration (Box 1)
    - United Services and Christian Education (Box 1)
    - Social Services, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - United Church Women of Ann Arbor (Box 1)
  - 1963
    - Administration, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - United Services and Christian Education (Box 1)
    - Social Services (Box 1)
    - United Church Women of Ann Arbor (Box 1)
  - 1964
    - Administration, 3 folders (Box 2)
    - United Services and Christian Education (Box 2)
    - Social Services (Box 2)
    - United Church Women of Ann Arbor (Box 2)
  - 1965
    - Administration, 3 folders (Box 2)
    - United Services and Christian Education (Box 2)
    - Social Services (Box 2)
    - United Church Women of Ann Arbor (Box 2)
  - 1966
    - Administration, 3 folders (Box 2)
    - United Services and Christian Education (Box 2)
    - Social Services, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - 10th Annual N.C.C.J. Human Relations Institute (Box 2)
    - United Church Women of Ann Arbor (Box 2)
  - 1967
    - Administration, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - United Services and Christian Education (Box 2)
    - Social Services (Box 2)
    - United Church Women of Ann Arbor (Box 2)
  - 1968, General (Box 2)
  - 1969, Annual Report (Box 2)